<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Nianci</title>
    <link>https://nianci-prog.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Nianci</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nianci-prog.github.io/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning Java through HackerRank</title>
      <link>https://nianci-prog.github.io/post/learning-java-hackerrank/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nianci-prog.github.io/post/learning-java-hackerrank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I practiced Java on &lt;strong&gt;HackerRank&lt;/strong&gt;, completing exercises that helped me strengthen my understanding of programming fundamentals, object-oriented concepts, and data manipulation techniques.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Through these exercises, I became more confident in Java syntax and problem-solving, preparing for more advanced projects and algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hackerrank-overview&#34;&gt;HackerRank Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HackerRank&lt;/strong&gt; is an online platform for coding practice and competitions.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It supports multiple programming languages — including &lt;strong&gt;Java&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;C++&lt;/strong&gt;, and more — and covers various domains such as &lt;strong&gt;algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;data structures&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;databases&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java OOP Notes from Saylor Academy</title>
      <link>https://nianci-prog.github.io/post/java-oop-notes-saylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nianci-prog.github.io/post/java-oop-notes-saylor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;saylor-academy-overview&#34;&gt;Saylor Academy Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Saylor Academy, founded by Michael J. Saylor in 2008, is a nonprofit online education platform headquartered in Washington, D.C., USA. It offers free, self-paced online courses covering humanities, business, mathematics, and science. Students can earn digital certificates, and some courses provide ACE-accredited college credits. By 2025, Saylor Academy has served over 2.5 million students worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-reflections&#34;&gt;Learning Reflections&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Studying Java object-oriented programming (OOP) helped me understand modularity and maintainability in programming. Through classes, objects, inheritance, encapsulation, abstraction, and polymorphism, I learned to design flexible, reusable program structures and map real-world concepts to code. Implementing examples like &lt;code&gt;SUV&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Student&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Calculator&lt;/code&gt; taught me how parent and child classes interact, how to override methods, and how to protect data, improving program organization and extensibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
